<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//Apache Software Foundation//DTD XDOC 1.0//EN"
  "http://maven.apache.org/dtd/xdoc_1_0.dtd">
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Daylight Chart - How-to</title>
    <author email="sualeh@hotmail.com">Sualeh Fatehi</author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="How-to">
      <subsection name="Save and Load Locations">
        <p>
          Daylight Chart has an option to save the locations list. This list
          will be saved in the Daylight Chart Locations List Format. It can be
          edited in any standard text editor, and loaded back into Daylight
          Chart.
        </p>
        <p>
          In addition to the Daylight Chart Locations List Format, the Daylight
          Chart program also supports loading of locations in the
          <a href="http://earth-info.nga.mil/gns/html/namefiles.htm">
            GNS Country Files
          </a>
          format. However, the data in the GNS Country Files does not contain
          daylight savings time information, so Daylight Chart will make a best
          guess of the time zone.
        </p>
        <p>
          The Daylight Chart program can load populated places in the USA in the
          <a href="http://geonames.usgs.gov/domestic/download_data.htm">
            GNIS file
          </a>
          format. The data in the GNIS files does not contain daylight savings
          time information, so Daylight Chart will make a best guess of the time
          zone.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Import and Export Reports">
        <p>
          Daylight Chart has an option to import and export reports. Report
          definitions are used to layout the Daylight Chart chart and data for
          the Adobe Acrobat PDF and HTML file formats.
        </p>
        <p>
          To customize a report, first export the report definition to a file.
          Then, modify the report definition using
          <a
            href="http://jasperforge.org/projects/ireport">
            iReport
          </a>
          . Next, you can import the modified report definition. The next time
          that you save the Daylight Chart chart in the the Adobe Acrobat PDF or
          HTML file formats, it will use the new report.
        </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
